# HIEBUKA NWACHUKWU

🗷 cenwachukwuu@gmail.com 🔇 cenwachukwu.netlify.com 📞 443 .523. 7863 🕈 Washington, DC

in cenwachukwu O cenwachukwu

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

As a software engineer with a background in scientific research, I am well-versed in problem-solving. While the scientific method helps me discover empirical truths and patterns, programming gives wings to my creative mind. Together, these skills help me communicate and implement clear and concise technical solutions.

# **EXPERIENCE**

### GENERAL ASSEMBLY, SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE, Student, Washington, DC

Sept. 2019 - Current

- Collaborate with a team of over 25 software engineers and UI/UX designers to design, create, test, and document client projects in an agile environment.
- Develop and design functional and efficient user interfaces with HTML, CSS, Javascript, and React.JS.
- Develop back-end language and framework proficiency with Python, Node.js, Express.js, and Django.
- Utilize multiple database technologies including NoSQL with MongoDB and Mongoose ORM, Postgres relational SQL with Django.
- Utilize a hands-on approach to develop real-world applications while maintaining two GitHub & GH Enterprise) profiles with a combined commit history of 400+ contributions

#### FiscalNote, Front Desk Assistant, Washington, DC

Nov. 2018 - Aug. 2019

- Enhanced the company's integrity and security by designing and implementing the use of an identification badge system.
- Provided excellent customer service by creating a client-facing area conducive enough for employees to perform at their optimum best and relaxing enough for the client's comfort.
- Managed the first line of communication between the company and prospective clients while maintaining a sense of urgency and excellent organizational skills.

#### University of Maryland Eastern Shore, Undergraduate Research Assistant, Princess Anne

- Mentored middle school students from three Maryland counties by training them on the collection of water quality data and microscopic identification of planktonic species.
- Collaborated with a multi-disciplinary research team focusing on the effects of citrus fruits as oviposition attractants or repellents against Anopheles gambiae mosquitoes.
- Documented and presented research findings at science symposiums and assisted with outreach activities in low- to mid-income communities.

# **PROJECTS**

Cotripper (Client Project) | github.com/CotripperPlatform/CoTrip

- Built an open-source full-stack application to facilitate an organized group travel experience for single mothers. My contributions included developing Banner and Modal component libraries and collaborating with a team of five engineers to build out the 'Book a trip' page. Over 25 engineers collaborated on this project using agile (kanban) methodologies, morning and afternoon standing-ups, and GitHub workflow.
- Technologies: CSS, Django, Enzyme, Jest, Node.JS, PostgreSQL, Python, React.JS, Storybook

theNotesCli | github.com/cenwachukwu/pythonCLIProject

- Developed a command-line application that has the ability to create, update and delete notes based on the user's request.
- Technologies: Peewee ORM, PostgreSQL, Psycopg2, Python

Medics | med-directory-cen.herokuapp.com/directory

- Developed a medical directory API that provides its users with the information of medical practitioners.
- Technologies: Express.JS, Heroku, MongoDB, Mongoose ORM, Node.JS

A Component Library | github.com/cenwachukwu/A-Component-Library

- Developed a library of different styles of buttons, forms, inputs, and image cards which saves users the time of building basic components from scratch.
- Technologies: Adobe XD, CSS, NPM, React, Storybook

# **SKILLS**

FRONT END DEVELOPMENT: Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, React.JS, Responsive Design

BACK END DEVELOPMENT: Django, Express.JS, MongoDB/Mongoose ORM, Node.JS, Peewee ORM, PostgreSQL, Python, Restful API, MVC frameworks, Data Modeling ADDITIONAL: Adobe XD, Agile, Git version control, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, NPM, Postman, VS Code, Object-oriented Programming

## **EDUCATION**

## GENERAL ASSEMBLY, SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE, WASHINGTON, DC

Software Engineering immersive

Sept. 2019 - Dec. 2019

UNIVERSITY OF MARYLAND EASTERN SHORE, PRINCESS ANNE, MD

Jan. 2014 - May 2017

Bsc Biology

## **AWARDS**